<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backdesk</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:7777/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://localhost:7777</link>
    <description>Digital content done right</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Contracting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:7777/articles/contractors-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:7777/articles/contractors-guide/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duis neque nisi, dapibus sed mattis et quis, nibh. Sed et dapibus nisl amet mattis, sed a rutrum accumsan sed. Suspendisse eu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving Github Pages with WinterSmith and Travis CI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:7777/articles/wintersmith-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:7777/articles/wintersmith-github/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duis neque nisi, dapibus sed mattis et quis, nibh. Sed et dapibus nisl amet mattis, sed a rutrum accumsan sed. Suspendisse eu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First, Does it Work?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:7777/articles/mobile-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:7777/articles/mobile-first/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve often wondered if a ‘Mobile First’ approach is more of an ideal than a concrete strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know mobile is (most likely) the forseeable future of the web and the pace of this revolution is rapidly driving an urgency for companies to have a strategy in place. A popular trend in strategy leans towards the concept of ‘Mobile First’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intention of this post is to share some of the conclusions I arrived at when studying the many definitons of ‘Mobile First’. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototypes-vs-flat-designs&quot;&gt;Prototypes vs. Flat Designs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had relatively few problems to solve when I first became a web developer. Designs were handed to me in the form of a Photoshop file which I did my utmost to make pixel perfect using HTML/CSS. There wasn’t a real requirement for responsive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days I engage a lot more with designers and at an earlier stage as well. In the past it might of been that design was a production phase where upon its completion you would receive assets to work with. That doesn’t quite cut the mustard any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned that it’s important to get involved with the concept at an early stage and from there start working towards building a prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess you could argue that the mobile aspect of the design is the simplest and for that reason - this is where we should start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;context-branching-vs-context-adaptation&quot;&gt;Context Branching vs. Context Adaptation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to think of audiences as contexts under which an application runs.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion a good example of this failure is Windows 8. But that’s probably a topic best left for another post!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>