<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backdesk</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:7777/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://localhost:7777</link>
    <description>Digital content done right</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Contracting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:7777/articles/contractors-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:7777/articles/contractors-guide/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A basic guide to weighing up the options and getting up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s great that you’re considering contracting and I know it can be hard to find the information you need to make an informed decision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-benefits&quot;&gt;The Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest appeal for me was the idea that I would gain more exposure to different technologies and approaches in a relatively short amount of time. I also tend to think of contracting as the only real way of staying ahead of new technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more obvious benefits are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larger income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible working hours and holiday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to work for multiple clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annual and sick leave are benefits you might take for granted in a permanent position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are entitled to a minimum of 5.6 weeks paid annual leave (28 days for someone working five days a week)”
— &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nidirect.gov.uk/holiday-entitlements&quot;&gt;NIDirect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies aren’t obliged to make a contractual provision for sick pay and if you’re working for a company that doesn’t run it’s own sick pay scheme then you’re stuck with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/statutory-sick-pay/overview&quot;&gt;Statutory Sick Pay&lt;/a&gt; (SSP) which pays a meager £87.55 a week. That’s £17.50 a day! If you were contracting you wouldn’t get paid anything at all but £17 is hardly a deal breaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid leave on the other hand is definitely a perk worth examining. An allocation of 28 days from which public holidays can be deducted so in effect a ballpark total of 20 days. In comparison a contractor could take as much unpaid leave they want by carefully planning their assignments around their own time and subsidising it with a larger net income.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;umbrella-or-limited&quot;&gt;Umbrella or Limited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out with an umbrella initially to keep cash coming in while I carefully investigated the option of a limited company. There are a lot of ‘formation’ companies out there but I chose to register my company for £15.00 through companies house.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing that the umbrella doesn’t stipulate fees for you leaving and nonsense like that you can use it for as long as you need. I would personally recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.access-a.co.uk/,&quot; title=&quot;Accessa Umbrella&quot;&gt;Accessa&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;accounting&quot;&gt;Accounting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a new business can be scary, especially if you’re new to everything. It’s often quoted that most businesses that fail within their infancy do so due to poor financial management. With that in mind you’re putting a lot of trust in whoever you choose to manage your books.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accountants don’t really understand the personal aspects of a startup and how reliant you are on them to tell you everything is in order. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I needed was a top level view of my business that I could discuss and interact over with an accountant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freeagent.co.uk/&quot;&gt;FreeAgent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;taxes&quot;&gt;Taxes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax law not only confuses me but also terrifies me. It seems that you’re guilty until proven innocent should you fall under HMRC’s spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving Github Pages with WinterSmith and Travis CI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:7777/articles/wintersmith-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:7777/articles/wintersmith-github/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duis neque nisi, dapibus sed mattis et quis, nibh. Sed et dapibus nisl amet mattis, sed a rutrum accumsan sed. Suspendisse eu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First, Does it Work?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:7777/articles/mobile-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:7777/articles/mobile-first/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve often wondered if a ‘Mobile First’ approach is more of an ideal than a concrete strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile is the future of the web and the pace of this revolution is rapidly driving an urgency for companies to have a strategy in place. A popular trend in strategy is the concept of ‘Mobile First’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototypes-vs-flat-designs&quot;&gt;Prototypes vs. Flat Designs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had relatively few problems to solve when I first became a web developer. Designs were handed to me in the form of a Photoshop file which I did my utmost to make pixel perfect using HTML/CSS. There wasn’t a real requirement for responsive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days I engage a lot more with designers and at an earlier stage as well. In the past it might of been that design was a production phase where upon its completion you would receive assets to work with. That doesn’t quite cut the mustard any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned that it’s important to get involved with the concept at an early stage and from there start working towards building a prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess you could argue that the mobile aspect of the design is the simplest and for that reason - this is where we should start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;context-branching-vs-context-adaptation&quot;&gt;Context Branching vs. Context Adaptation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to think of audiences as contexts under which an application runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion a good example of this failure is Windows 8. But that’s probably a topic best left for another post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;copy&quot;&gt;Copy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you write and revise copy should also be a consideration in an adaptive solution. A moderately large block of copy might look great on the higher resolutions but lengthly and overkill on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>